National Negro Opera Company Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
1959, Nov. 11 Benefit dinner, 2610 3rd Street N.E., Washington, D.C. (private residence)
1960, Feb. 14 National Negro Opera Foundation presented The Ordering of Moses, in cooperation with the Association of Negro Life and History, Lisner Auditorium, Washington, D.C.
1960, Sept. 11 Chicago Negro Opera Guild presented Opera Festival, Dunbar High School Auditorium, Chicago
1960, Nov. 18 Evelyn Greene, in concert, Metropolitan A.M.E. Church, Washington, D.C. (sponsored by the Metropolitian A.M.E. Church's Pastor's Aid and Hospitality Clubs)
1960, Dec. 2 National Negro Opera Foundation and Washington Guild presented 1960 Spectacular Fashions in Couturere Parisienne, Metropolitian A.M.E. Church, Washington, D.C.
1961, Feb. 19 National Negro Opera Foundation and Chicago Opera Guild held reception honoring Mary Cardwell Dawson, and presented Chicago Sustaining Committee, Palmer House, Chicago
1961, Apr. 23 Washington Youth Opera Guild held "Talented Tots to Teens" fashion musicale and dance show, Jewish Community Center, Washington, D.C.
1961, June 3-4 National Negro Opera Foundation, in cooperation New York, Washington, Baltimore, Pittsburgh and Chicago Opera Guilds held two-day opera meet, Statler Hotel, Washington, D.C.
1961, July 16 The Ordering of Moses performed at a benefit performance for National Negro Opera Company and Chicago Opera Guild, Dunbar High School Auditorium, Chicago
1962, Mar. 19 Mary Cardwell Dawson died, Washington, D.C.
1962, May 17 New York Guild Opera Workshop performed The Bohemian Girl, Beulah Wesleyan Auditorium, New York
1962, Oct. 7 Chicago Negro Opera Guild performed in Opera Festival, Dunbar High School Auditorium
1965, Sept. 19 Chicago Opera Guild performed concertized excerpts from Aida, Faust, Il Travatore and Masked Ball, McCormack Place, Chicago (in memory of Mary Cardwell Dawson)
1994, May 25 Dedication of an official historical marker commemorating the National Negro Opera Company at the site of the old Cardwell School of Music, 7101 Apple Street, Pittsburgh, Pa.
1997, July 27 Tribute to Madame Mary Cardwell Dawson and the National Negro Opera Company, Carnegie Library of Homestead Music Hall, Pittsburgh, Pa.
Scope and Content Note
The National Negro Opera Company was the first African-American opera company in the United States. The collection spans the years 1879-1997, with the bulk of the material dated 1930-1962. The collection documents not only the activities of the company, but also the life and career of its founder Mary Cardwell Dawson.
The Correspondence series includes business and personal correspondence to and from many prominent musical figures of the period, such as Marian Anderson, Muriel Rahn, Robert McFerrin, and Todd Duncan. It also includes items from political and community leaders, including Eleanor Roosevelt, P. L. Prattis, and Mary MacLeod Bethune. Of particular interest is correspondence with Clarence Cameron White, composer of Ouanga, an opera performed by the National Negro Opera Company in 1956.
Most of the photographs in the Photographs series feature individuals and groups involved in the activities of the National Negro Opera Company, the Cardwell Dawson Chorus, the NNOC's various membership guilds, and other affiliated groups. There are many inscribed photographs in the collection that are indicated as such in the finding aid. The series is primarily comprised of publicity stills of performers, but there is also a significant amount of production photographs of casts (in and out of costume), rehearsals, and performances. In addition, there are photographs of various city guild administrative boards and committees. Personal photographs of Dawson family members are also included. Although every attempt has been made to identify individuals found in the photographs, many images of individual and groups remain unidentified. As a result, the series is subdivided into two subseries: photographs that are identified and ones that have been unable to be identified.
The Programs and Promotional Materials series contains a substantial number of programs and related promotional materials, including posters, flyers, press releases, funding solicitation letters, letters announcing events, tickets, and invitations.
Both the Administrative and Financial Papers series provide a record of the National Negro Opera Company's business activities. Included among these materials are charters, by-laws, lists of officers and board members, planning information, minutes of meetings, and other documents relating to the company, to the National Negro Opera Foundation, and to other organizations and committees.
Datable and identifiable budgets and financial reports are arranged in chronological order, with undated reports filed separately. Several income and expense reports from productions are included. Bank statements and related materials are arranged in alphabetical order by institution. Contracts are filed alphabetically by contractee or subject. The majority of the contracts are arranged by performer, with other types of contracts filed within.
Materials relating to ticket sales retain any pre-existing groupings, but, due to incomplete labelling, no further attempt was made to arrange these materials. Similar treatment has been given to the bills and receipts and handwritten notes. Appointment books and calendars have been arranged chronologically. Miscellaneous administrative papers, including advertising, insurance, and other materials complete the Administrative Papers series.
The Clippings series contains items from the 1930s that chronicle Mrs. Dawson's activities prior to the founding of the National Negro Opera Company. It also contains reviews of performances from the 1940s and 1950s. The majority of these articles are drawn from major African-American newspapers, such as the Washington Afro-American and the Chicago Defender.
The Scrapbooks series includes pasted clippings dating from the 1940s and 1950s from a disassembled scrapbook. There are also paste-up pages containing items clipped from National Negro Opera Company programs. A scrapbook labeled "National Negro Opera Foundation, Inc." contains small advertising posters, clippings, and copies of early photographs cut from National Negro Opera Company publications.
The Address Lists and Address Books series includes a large number of address lists containing information that is sometimes partially identified and in various stages of completion. Longer, identified lists have been housed separately. The remaining lists have been separated according to those with designations and those without. In addition to loose-leaf address lists, the collection contains over forty bound address books, each of which has been assigned a number and filed in numerical order.
The Notebooks series (both disassembled and intact) contains financial and budget materials, secretarial and stenographer notes, telephone logs, and other items that highlight the daily office operations of the National Negro Opera Company and related organizations in which Mary Cardwell Dawson was involved.
Music in the collection is arranged alphabetically by composer. This series contains such items as songs by Lillian Evanti (a singer in NNOC's first operatic production), a manuscript arrangement by NNOC singer Roy O'Loughlin of O Hear Me Lord from R. Nathaniel Dett's Ordering of Moses, a song written for the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs by Eva Jessye, and manuscripts by Benjamin Francisco Jaime. This series also contains script fragments and synopses, nearly half of which consist of scenes from Ordering of Moses. The remainder of these are arranged alphabetically by title of production.
The Books series contains various items, including six musical textbooks, a 1951 National Council of Negro Women yearbook and Tones and Overtones, an Alabama State College, Department of Music serial that was used by Mary Cardwell Dawson. Several textbooks contain notes written by Dawson, with one book containing thirty handwritten lectures dating from around 1919-1920. A list of books not retained with this collection can be examined in the Music Division collections file folder for the National Negro Opera Company Collection.
The Realia series includes 275 metal printing plates, the majority of which contain reverse photographic images of individuals and groups. These images were reproduced in publications, newspaper articles, programs, brochures and other publicity materials. Most plates/blocks appear to be reverse images taken from original photographs found in the collection.
This series also contains two large transfer storage boxes and four smaller boxes (representing approximately nine linear feet of shelf space) of opera stage costumes. These are currently stored off-site and can be made available upon request.
The La Julia Rhea Gift contains materials given to the Library of Congress Music Division by the family of Ms. Rhea, who was the first black artist to star with a major opera company. These materials document her career and her struggles in overcoming discrimination within the operatic profession. She appeared in the title role in the National Negro Opera Company's first production of Verdi's Aida on August 29, 1941. The gift includes autobiographical and biographical materials, a Town Hall program from November 9, 1943, scrapbooks, and clippings.
The Walter M. Dawson Papers series contains materials relating to Mary Cardwell Dawson's husband who was personally and financially supportive of his wife's musical endeavors. He served as the company's public relations director, publicity director, and comptroller during the National Negro Opera Company's active years. The National Negro Opera Company Collection as a whole contains materials relating to Walter M. Dawson's involvement with the company. The Walter M. Dawson Papers series, on the other hand, contains materials relating to Mr. Dawson's career as a master electrician with the General Services Administration. While this material does not directly relate to the National Negro Opera Company, it is of cultural and historical interest for drawing attention to Mr. Dawson's role in challenging discrimination in the federal government and electricians' unions. Having been denied membership in the AFL-CIO, he co-founded the Association of Electricians, Metropolitan Washington, D.C. Area, in 1958.
Organization of the National Negro Opera Company Collection
The National Negro Opera Company Collection is organized in fourteen series:
Correspondence, 1934-1970
Photographs, 1925-1994
Programs and Promotional Materials, 1926-1997
Administrative Papers, 1912-1961
Financial Papers, 1936-1962
Clippings, 1931-1997
Scrapbooks, circa 1940-1961
Address Lists and Address Books, 1940-1961
Notebooks, 1932-1961
Music, 1879-1961
Books, 1889-1955
Realia, circa 1928-1961
La Julia Rhea Gift, 1930s-1989
Walter M. Dawson Papers, 1925-1970
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006568166
Container List
- Correspondence, 1934-1970, (193 folders) (Box 7-12)
  Correspondence with individuals, companies, and organizations that document the National Negro Opera Company's efforts and difficulties in producing operas during the 1940s and into the early 1960s. A folder containing correspondence of Jeanna Edwards was removed from the collection by Barbara Edwards Lee, on April 12, 1996. Correspondence of Etta Moten was missing from the collection at the time the finding aid was coded.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of individual or company and chronologically therein.
  - A. & P. Stores, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - A-B-C Desk and Partition Company, 1944 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - A. C. Powell Sr. Fund, Inc., New York (Kate C. Hicks, Executive Director), 1945 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Abraham Lincoln Centre, Chicago (Morris Topchevsky), 1943 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Adams, A. Cyrus, 1941, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Admiral Corporation, 1952 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Aero Advertising Company, 1952 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - African Academy of Arts and Research, undated (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Afro-American Newspaper, Baltimore (W. I. Gibson, Editor; Carl Murphy, Sr., President), 1945, 1950, 1952, 1958 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Afro-American Newspaper, Washington, D.C. (Art Carter), 1952, 1960 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Afro Arts Theatre Presents, 1956 (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Aladden Rug & Furniture Cleaners, 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Albi, Fred, 1952 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Albright, Joseph Francis, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Alexander, Robert W., 1949 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Alfred Scott Concert Publications, New York (Stanley Scott, Publisher), 1956 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Alfredo, Mr., 1949, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/2)
  - All American Bus Line (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/2)
  - All State Insurance Company, 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Allen, Mary C., 1959 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Allen, Steve, 1955 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Allers, Franz, 1956 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Allied Arts Corporation, 1952 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Allstate Insurance Company, 1952 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, New York (Carol Lewis), 1956 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Inc. Alpha Gamma Lambda Chapter, 1956 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Alter, Sadie V. (Mrs. David Alter), 1948-1958 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers, 1951 (Box-folder 7/2)
  - American Beauty Products Company, 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/2)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1944 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - American Federation of Musicians. Local 802, New York (Mr. Feinberg, Secretary), 1944 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - American Federation of Musicians. Feldman vs. Dawson, 1950 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - American Federation of Musicians, Musicians' Protective Union, Local 161, Washington, D.C., (Harry C. Manvell, Treasurer; Paul J. Schwarz, President), 1943, 1949 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - American Finance Company, 1951 (Box-folder 7/3)
  - American Guild of Musical Artists, Inc., 1949-1960 (Box-folder 7/4)
  - American Legion Band, 1950, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/5)
  - American National Theatre and Academy, 1956 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - American Negro Emancipation Centennial, Chicago. (James E. Stamps, Chairman, Board of Trustees), 1960 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - American Red Cross, 1952 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - American Security & Trust Company, Washington, D.C. (Frederick P. H. Siddons, Vice President), 1946, 1950, 1952 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), 1956 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Amusement Publishing Company (David H. Light, Manager), 1954 and undated (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Anderson, Alice, 1947 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Anderson, Elizabeth, 1959 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Anderson, Georgia C., 1958-1960 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Anderson, J. C., 1936 (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Anderson, Marian, 1957-1958 see also Photographs: Anderson, Marian (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Andrew F. Jackson & Associates (Washington, D.C.), 1956, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Andrews, Ismay R., 1944 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Andrews, Lillian Foster (Co-Chairman, Friends of the Opera Committee), 1958 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Anglin, John, 1948 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Annin Brothers Flag Company, 1951 (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Arcus Simplex Ticket Company, 1944-1956 (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Arlington County, Virginia (Government), 1960 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Armour & Company (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Arrington, Fannie, 1958 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Artcraft Lithograph and Printing Company, (New York), 1956-1957 (Box-folder 7/9)
  - Associated Counselors International, Washington, D.C. (Public Relations), 1960 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Associated Dist's (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Associated Negro Press, Chicago (Claude A. Barnett, Director), 1943 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Associated Publishers Inc., (New York), 1955 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Association of Music Teachers in Negro Schools (J. Harold Brown, Chairman), 1939 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Association of Theatrical Press Agents, 1953 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Atcherson, James, 1960 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Atchison & Keller, Inc., (Washington, D.C.), 1959 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Atlantic Brewing Company, (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Atlas Brewing Company, (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Austria. Embassy. (Wilfried Platzer, Ambassador), 1959 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Auth Brothers, Inc., (Washington, D.C.), 1960 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Avalone, Blanche, 1948-1962, Name is spelled "Avaloni" on a few programs. (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Ayers, Lemuel, 1955 (Box-folder 7/12)
  - Bacchus, Norma C., 1944, 1959 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Backus, C. W., 1944 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Bailey Hotel (Pittsburgh), 1954 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - Baker, Edith E. (Field Director, New York Guild, NNOC), 1958-1959 (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Baker, Harry W., 1942 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Baldwin Ice Cream Company (Chicago), 1957 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Banks, L. L., 1952 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Banks, Ruth E., 1940 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barber, Arthur, 1954 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barbour, Saphronia, 1948, 1958, Ms. Barbour was a sister of Mary Cardwell Dawson. (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barham, Edwin L., 1956 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barnes, Leroy E., 1969, Letter to Walter M. Dawson in regard to the reorganization of a Boy Scout troop. (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barnett, Claude, 1952 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barnett Aden Gallery, New York (Alonzo J. Aden, Director),1947, 1959 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Barton, Moselle, 1949, 1953 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Baskett, Millie, 1958 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Bass, Grace, 1960 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Bastian Brothers Company, (Pittsburgh), 1934 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Battle, Ada, 1944 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Bauer & Black, (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Baylor, Donald, 1953 (Box-folder 7/15)
  - Beasley, Moses W., Jr., 1959 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Beaumont & Hohman, Inc., 1955 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Beavers, Charles T., 1955 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Becker, E. D., 1954 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Becker, Ralph E. (Law Offices: Brookhart, Becker & Dorsey, Washington, D.C.), 1957 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Beckman, Ola, 1954, 1959 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Beckley-Cardy (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Beckom, O'Labrice C. (Women's Committee of Pittsburgh), 1954, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Belcher, Annie, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Belden Manufacturing Company, (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Bell, Alice, 1953 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Bell, Gertrude Johnson, 1954 (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Bell, Theresa, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 7/17)
  - Bell Telephone Company, 1954 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Bellmore Service, Inc., 1957 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Benedum, M. L., 1954 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Bennett, Brenda, 1944 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Benson, Al, 1952 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Bergman's Laundry, Washington, D.C. (Public Relations), 1960 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Bernstein, Mr. (Manager, Local 169, A.C.W.A.), 1944 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Bernswanger, W. E., 1954 (Box-folder 7/18)
  - Bethune, Mary McCleod, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 7/19)
  - Baylom, Ramona, 1952 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Better Business Bureau of Pittsburgh, 1954 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Better Business Bureau of Washington, D.C., 1945 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Bettis, Mrs. E. C., 1954 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Betts, Gladys, 1954 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Bigelow, Alice, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Billboard (Magazine), 1945 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Bimparns, Lucille, undated (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Bing, Rudolf, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Birkim, Marian, 1954 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Blake, Gloria, 1956 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Block, Leonard, 1951 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Boatner, Adelaide, 1956 (Box-folder 7/20)
  - Bobitt-Gardner, Anna (Director, Academy of Piano-forte and Dramatics, Boston), 1946-1959 and undated (Box-folder 7/21)
  - Bolden, Frank, 1954 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bolds, Jenny, 1960 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Booker, J. R., 1954 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Booker, Lillian E., 1944 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Booker, Naomi, 1957 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Boone, Nealy, 1962 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Boosey and Hawkes, Inc., 1955 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Booth, Alan, 1955 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Borden Company (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Borg-Warner Corporation (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Boris, Ruthanna, undated (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bostic, Joe, 1955 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bostick, Julius A., 1952 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bourne, J. Franklyn, 1955 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bow, Marguerite S., 1943 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bowen-Blair, Stephanie, 1955 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bowersock, J. D., 1958, 1960 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bowes, Major, 1939, Letter requesting an opportunity for the Cardwell Dawson Singers to appear on the Major Bowes program. (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bowes, Wilhimenia, 1952 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bowman Dairy Company (Chicago), 1952 (Box-folder 7/22)
  - Bracken, Tom, 1956 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Bradford, Gaines T., 1954-1955 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Bradley, Thelma J., 1949 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Bradshaw, Ann Regina, 1958 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Bragg, Bertha, 1959 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Branch, Mary Nell, 1960 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Branche, Blanche, 1961 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Brent, Albert Ross, 1955 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Brewing, Robert, 1961 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Briggs, Lucinda A., 1953 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Briggs, Raymond C., 1960 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Bright-Knapp, Bertha, 1945 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Brimer, T. J., 1959 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Britt, James H., 1960 (Box-folder 7/23)
  - Bromley, Darline B., 1954 (Box-folder 7/24)
  - Brooks, Albert N. D., 1959 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brooks, Caroll, 1944 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brooks, Catherine, 1944, 1953 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brott, Lou (Public Relations - Washington, D.C.), 1960 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Anita Patti, 1936 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Calden, 1959 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Chamberlain, 1944 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Constance, 1958 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Debria, 1959 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Ervin, 1954 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, George, 1949 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Homer, Mrs., 1958 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Juanita Welch (Jeanette), 1959 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Lovania, 1960 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Martha C., 1956 (Box-folder 7/25)
  - Brown, Oscar C., 1952-1959 (Box-folder 7/26)
  - Brown, W. Roderick, Mrs., 1954 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Brown, William H., 1951 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Brown Sign Company, Washington, D.C. (Chauncey Brown), 1952 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Browne, Anne Wiggins, 1936 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Brunswick-Blake-Collender Company (Chicago), 1952, Contains no correspondence. (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Bryant, Mr., undated (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Buchanan, Charles, 1951 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Buchanan, Walter, Mrs., 1936 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Buckingham Super Market, 1960, 1962 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Buick Company (Pittsburgh Office), 1954 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Bunche, Ralph J., 1950, 1959 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Burdette, John, 1946 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Burgess, Harry T. and Marion, 1970, Holiday card addressed to Walter Dawson. (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Burma. Embassy. (U Win, Ambassador, and Mrs.), 1959 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Burrell, C. A., 1954 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Burrelle's Press Clipping Bureau, Inc. (New York), undated (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Business and Professional Association of Pittsburgh, undated (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Butcher, Beatrice Bowen, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Butcher, James W., 1954 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Byars, Rufus, 1953 (Box-folder 7/27)
  - Bynam, George, 1952 (Box-folder 7/27)